星际之门 亚特兰蒂斯
前情提要
Previously on Stargate Atlantis...
不论我们打算藏在这颗星球的什么地方
No matter were we try to hide
on this planet,
复制体的卫星都将会找到我们
the Replicator satellite
will be able to track us.
Atlantis要离开这颗星球
Atlantis is leaving.
- 我们飞行的高度不够
- 我们的能量不够
- We're not flying high enough.
- We don't have enough power.
我们迷路了
We are lost.
我们过早的跌出了超空间
我对我们在什么地方毫无头绪
We dropped out of hyperspace way
too soon. I have no idea where we are.
她没有反应 瞳孔也反应迟钝
She's unresponsive
and her pupils are sluggish.
在我们到那里以前
准备好手术室和扫描仪
Prep the OR and have the scanner
ready when we get there.
一些主要的管线受到光束扫射的影响
Several conduits were affected
by the brush with the beam.
她出现脑水肿
She's suffering from cerebral oedema,
而且可能已经导致实质性的脑损伤
which may have caused
substantial brain damage.
- 那是什么
- 小行星带?
- What is that?
- An asteroid belt?
我们要用Drone导弹在小行星带中
开辟出一条通道来
We're gonna clear a path through
the belt by firing our drones.
Elizabeth快不行了 如果想要救她
我们必须现在就动手
Elizabeth's crashing. If we
do this thing, we need to do it now.
你做了什么
What did you do?
- 我重新激活了纳米元件
- 该死 McKay
- I reactivated the nanites.
- Dammit!
听着 我100%肯定它们不会控制她
也不会和别的复制体联系
But I'm certain they're not gonna try
to take her over or contact the others!
这是一个非常糟糕的主意
This is a very bad idea.
那里有拥有ZPM的星球吗
There's a planet out there with ZPMs?
那里是复制体的老家
That would be the Replicator homeworld.
你是不是有想去打劫的念头?
You feel up to a heist?
好了 当我说可以了
就试试看左边的线
OK, when I say,
go ahead and try the left one.
上帝啊 我说了"要等我说可以了"
Geez!
I said, "when I say!"
我以为你已经说了
I thought you did say!
进展如何 伙计们
How's it going, boys?
如果不是他每2秒钟就企图杀死我一次
We'd be making a lot more progress
我们的进展会更大
if Timmy Torture over here wasn't
trying to kill me every 2 sec.
我没有企图杀死他
I'm not trying to kill him.
那么 你们到底能不能让它进行超空间跳跃?
So, can you make it
jump into hyperspace or not?
是的 我想可以
Yes, I think so.
- 你想你可以?
- 是的 我想
- You think so?
- Yes, think.
你说过你能做到的
You said you could do it.
纠正一下 我说过"可能"做到
Correction I said "probably" do it.
是的 他在一个他上次接近升天时
创立的算法上遇到点麻烦
Yes, he has trouble with an algorithm
he created during his near-ascension.
这是难以想象的复杂的物理学 你明白么
This is unbelievably complex
physics here, alright?
我是说 它使得线性理论
看上去像是非线性动力学
I mean, it makes string theory look
like non-linear dynamics.
而且即使我可以让它工作
Even if I do get it working,
依然会有成千上万个地方
可能出现十分可怕的错误
there's still a thousand things
that could go terribly, terribly wrong.
我明白了 这很困难
万分之一的机会 等等 等等...
I get it, it's difficult.
Million-to-one odds...
你还需要什么东西么
抑或你就是来这里打击我们的?
Was there something else you needed,
or were you here to prod and belittle?
不 不
No, not.
不只是这样
Not merely.
还有一个问题我们必须思考
There's another problem
we need to be thinking about.
例如 我们到了那以后该怎么做
Such as, what do we do
when we get there?
找到能跳进超空间的办法
也许是其中最简单的部分
Getting this thing to jump
into hyperspace may be easy.
潜入城市 偷走ZPM
Infiltrating the city, stealing the ZPM,
然后再全身而退 我觉得那有些风险
and getting out,
I think that's a little dicey.
退一步说
To say the least.
- 我已经考虑过这个问题了
- 然后呢
- I've been thinking about that.
- And?
我认为如果我们要成功的话
And I think that if we stand
any chance of succeeding,
我们得需要些帮助
we're gonna need some help.
找谁帮忙
From who?
想去做次旅行么
Feel like taking a trip?
星际之门 亚特兰蒂斯
第04季 第02集
生命线
Season 4 Episode 02
- Lifeline (v. 1.00) -
我认为在你体内的纳米元件
The nanites inside you,
如果能短距离靠近
I think, if we got them
in close proximity
人形复制体的城市
to the human-form Replicator's city,
我就能操作它们远程侵入
I'd be able to manipulate them
to remotely hack
复制体的主机
into the Replicator mainframe.
这样我们就能够找到
最近的ZPM和最快进出的路
We'd be able to find out the closest ZPM
and the quickest way to get in and out.
不但如此 同时我们还能追踪它们的行动
Not only that, we'd be able to track
their movement as well.
在它们发现我们之前就能知道它们要来了
We'll know they're coming
before they spot us.
但这样也不能排除危险
Which does not eliminate the danger.
差很多
Far from it.
但确实给我们相当大的优势
But it does give us a significant edge.
如果复制体控制了我体内的
纳米元件会怎么样
What happens if the Replicators take
control of the nanites inside me?
- 它们不会 我会阻止所有的尝试...
- 但是如果它们成功了呢
- They won't. I'd block any attempt...
- But if they do?
我已经让Rodney在纳米元件的
代码里加入了一个终止开关
I ordered Rodney to write a kill switch
into the nanites' code.
如果我们触发程序
就会将他们无效化
If we trigger the program,
it'll neutralize them.
无效化 你是说使它们停止工作?
Neutralize them,
you mean shut them off?
是的
Yes.
而你说过是这些纳米元件
是我可以维持生命的全部原因
And you said the nanites are
all that are keeping me alive.
是的
They are.
如果我们关掉它们 就会...
If we shut them off, it will...
杀死你
kill you.
但这是不会发生的
But that's not gonna happen.
对么
Alright?
我已经让Rodney盯紧这些小混蛋
确保它们不会捣乱
I've ordered Rodney to keep an eye
on the bastards, make sure they behave.
若不是因为这是此次任务成功的唯一机会
We would not ask this
of you if it was not
我们也不会请求你这么做的
the only chance of
this mission succeeding.
她说得对 如果我们弄不到ZPM 大家都会...
She's right, if we don't get hold
of a ZPM, the City and everyone in...
我们什么时候出发
When do we leave?
就现在
Right now.
什么 等等
What? Wait,
不 不 不 不是现在
听着 我还没有最终完成动力...
No... not right now. Look, I haven't
finished finalizing the power distrib...
那就完成它 我们要出发了
Finalize it. We need to move.
你不会有事的 Elizabeth
You're gonna be OK, Elizabeth.
尽管如此
Still,
我要你们所有人都紧紧的盯住我
I would like all of you
to keep a very close eye on me,
一旦有任何可疑的举动
and the first sign
of any suspicious behavior,
要毫不犹豫的启动终止程序
do not hesitate
with that kill switch.
- 好的 但这是不会发生的...
- John 我是说真的
- OK, but that's not gonna happen...
- John, I mean it.
嘿 Teyla
Hey, Teyla!
等等
Wait up.
我需要你留在这儿
I'm gonna need you
to sit this one out.
John 如果这次任务不能成功的话...
John, if this mission is not successful
Zelenka认为他找到了一个
Zelenka thinks he found a planet
适合人类生存的行星
that can sustain human life.
他十分有信心可以通过
一次跳跃就让城市到达那里
He's fairly confident that he can get
the City there in one jump.
没有护盾 我们将无法降落
Without the shields,
we will be unable to land.
我知道 我们也没有足够的能量
来建立环绕轨道
I know. We won't even have enough
power to establish orbit.
所以要进行低空飞越
让所有人都坐上Jumper
You're gonna have to do a fly-by,
and get everybody else in the Jumper.
- 你是说放弃这座城市
- 是的 如果走到那一步的话
- You mean abandon the City.
- Well, if it comes to that.
好了 这些人将会需要一位领导
Alright, these people
are gonna need a leader.
能保证他们活下去
把他们团结在一起的人 更重要的是
Somebody who can keep them alive, keep
them together, more importantly, not
不让他们放弃希望
let them give up hope.
那个人就是你 Teyla
That's you, Teyla.
- John...
- 听着 如果我12个小时后没回来
Look, if I'm not back twelve hours,
就下命令
give the order.
好了
Alright.
开始
Now.
- 你肯定?
- 是的
- Are you certain?
- Yes.
- 我这么问是因为上一次你不够确定...
- Radek
I only ask 'cause the last time you were
less than definitive in your answer...
好吧
Alright.
- 行了
- 是么
- OK.
- Yes?
- 我想我们成功了
- 很好 很好 现在...
- I think we got it.
- Good, good, now...
现在只要我们不在第一次跳跃时
now, as long as we don't
burn up all of the power
就耗尽所有的能量 那么...
on the initial jump, then...
是的 是的 好的 是的
Yes, yes, right, OK.
我现在就走
I'll leave now.
- 准备好了吗
- 是的 听着 我依然不确定这能否成功
- You ready?
- Yes. I'm not sure if it's gonna work,
我是说 我已经做了所有我能做的来确保...
I've done everything
I can to make it.
Sheppard 我们准备好了
Sheppard, we're ready.
好了 Teyla 我们准备好出发了
Alright Teyla, we're ready to launch.
明白
Understood.
打开Jumper船坞的舱门
Open the Jumper bay doors.
记住 我们离开以后别开什么疯狂派对
Remember, no wild parties
while we're gone.
我们会努力保持克制的
We will try to restrain ourselves.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
好的 我们出发
Alright, here we go.
Rodney 准备好了吗
Rodney, you ready?
我有没有提过这不一定会成功
我们同样有可能过早
Did I mention that this might not work?
And that we could either drop out of
跌出超空间
然后搁浅在深层空间中心
hyperspace prematurely and end up
stranded in the middle of deep space,
或者可能在我按下按钮时就被蒸发了
or quite possibly, be vaporized
the moment I touch that.
回答那个该死的问题就可以了
Just answer the damn question.
是的 准备好了
Yeah, I'm ready.
好的 坐下
Good, sit down.
开始吧
Here goes.
好的 打开超空间窗口 3
OK, opening
hyperspace window in three,
two,
1...
one...
我的天啊 这...这太美丽了
Oh my! that's... beautiful.
是的
Yeah, it is.
就像是艾尔文森林一样
(Elwynn forest 魔兽世界中的地图 这位仁兄是粉丝)
It's like Elwynn Forest.
没什么
Oh, nothing, it's
那是魔兽世界里的一片大地
one of the lands in Warcraft.
那是我玩的一个游戏
That's a game I play.
好吧 偶尔
Well, occasionally.
你没事吧
You gonna be OK?
是的 是的 我只是...你知道
我不是经常来地外世界
Yeah, I just... you know,
I don't get to get offworld much,
或者说 几乎没有过
or ever, hardly.
你最好拍张照 我们不会在这儿呆很久
You'd better take a picture
we're not gonna be here long.
对 好主意
Right, good idea.
这里是Carter上校 呼叫Apollo号
This is Colonel Carter
calling the Apollo.
Ellis上校 收到了么
Colonel Ellis, do you read?
很清楚 上校
Five by five, Colonel.
我们已经穿过星门 准备好传送
We've stepped through the Gate
and are ready for transport.
- 不 等等 等等...
- 准备
- No, wait...
- Stand-by.
欢迎来到天马星系 上校
Welcome to the Pegasus galaxy, Colonel.
谢谢 依然没有Atlantis的消息?
Thank you.
Still no word from Atlantis?
什么也没有
Nothing.
我已经用你建议的对传感器阵列的修正
I've been going over the specs
对这片空间重新进行了察看
for these modifications you're proposing
for the sensor array.
你要求增加5倍的能量?
You're asking for a five-fold increase
in power consumption?
还想从另外6个关键系统调拨部件
Plus, you want to cannibalize parts
from half a dozen other key
包括亚空间通讯系统
systems, including
subspace communications.
说的对
That's correct.
如果他们试图和我们联系 怎么办
What if they try and contact us?
如果他们能的话 应该已经做了
If they could, they would have done it.
所有这些都基于
All of this is based on the assumption
假设他们过早跌出超空间的基础上
that they dropped out
of hyperspace early.
是的 我们相信那是最有可能的情形
Yeah, we believe
that's the most likely scenario.
好吧 我们开始吧
Alright, let's do it.
祝贺你 Rodney
Congratulations, Rodney.
你的超空间引擎成功了
Your hyperdrive worked.
不幸的是 信不信由你
Unfortunately, believe it or not,
事实上Zelenka是对的
Zelenka was actually right.
我们在跳跃上消耗了
We burned up way more power on the jump
比预期更多的能量
than we expected.
什么意思 我们回不去了?
What are you saying?
We can't get back?
不 不 我说的是...
No, what I am saying is that the...
实际上 那正是我要说的
Actually,
that's exactly what I'm saying.
我认为 只要我们偷到ZPM
就可以利用它的能量
I suppose, once we steal the ZPM,
I could utilise its power.
- 我要确认一下我没有过载...
- 让我们一步一步来 好么
- Need to make sure I don't overload...
- Let's take this one step at a time!
先做重要的事
First things first.
让我们想想如何弄到ZPM
Let's worry about getting the ZPM.
对
Right.
- 好吧 我要尝试初始化连接
- 你需要我做什么
- I'm gonna try to initialize the link.
- What do you want me to do?
什么也不用做 就坐在那
完全是无线连接的
Nothing. Just sit there.
It's completely wireless.
如果有什么东西涌入你的大脑就告诉我
Let me know if anything
pops into your mind.
什么意思
What do you mean?
是我会感知到什么
Will I just sort of sense something,
还是更加...
or is it more of a...
上帝啊
Oh, my God.
我做到了
I did it.
我是说 她做到了
I mean, she did it.
但我们动作要迅速
尽管她的纳米元件只在"潜水模式"
But we have to move fast. Even though
her nanites are in lurking mode,
但用不了多久复制体就会发现
有别的玩家加入了游戏
won't take long for them to figure out
another player has joined the game.
你感觉如何 Elizabeth
How you feeling, Elizabeth?
很奇怪
Very strange.
我突然可以在面前看到整个城市
I can suddenly see the entire city
directly in front of me.
每一条通道 每一间房间...
Every corridor, every single room...
那边
That way.
ZPM
The ZPM.
第四象限 最高层 很容易接近
周围几乎没有人
Fourth quadrant, top level, easy access.
There's hardly anyone around.
好的 对我来说是个好消息
Alright, works for me.
好的 我们着陆了
Rodney和Elizabeth呆在这儿
Alright, we're down.
Rodney, stay here with Elizabeth,
过滤情报 你们可以通过无线电指引我们
keep sifting through the intel.
You guys can guide us through by radio.
Jumper后方左侧20米处
Twenty meters to the left
behind the jumper,
有个入口
there's an access door.
往下走过一段楼梯
Down one flight of stairs,
会进入7号附属通道
you'll enter auxiliary corridor seven.
现在快去 那里没人
Go now, it's clear.
我们到达通道了
We're at the corridor.
往右
Go right.
走6.5米
At 6.5 meters,
- 应该有另一个通道
- 好的 我们看到了
- there should be another corridor.
- OK, we see it.
向左 等等 回去
Turn left. Wait! Go back!
没事 他没看到你们
It's alright, he didn't see you.
真的吗 这些你都知道?
Really? You know that?
是的 就像我说的 非常奇怪
Yeah. Like I said, it's very strange.
我们现在能过去了吗
Can we go now?
是的 去吧
Yes, go.
往左 然后往右
Turn left, then right.
它应该就在你们面前
It should be directly in front of you.
是的 我看到它了
Yeah, I see it.
别着急 野人(Chewie 星球大战里的)
Hold up, Chewie.
我们把它拔出来的时候
它们不就注意到了么
Aren't they gonna notice
when we pull the plug on this thing?
很有可能 但是它们有几十个ZPM
Probably,
but they've got dozens of ZPMs.
希望他们发现的时候 我们早已远走高飞
Let's just hope that they don't notice
until we're long gone.
那只是你一厢情愿而已
That's wishful thinking.
我们依然是安全的吗
We still in the clear?
离你们2条通道的地方
有一小队复制体 正朝你们那里过去
There's a small group of Replicators
two corridors over, heading your way,
所以你们动作必须快点儿
so you need to move quickly.
到手了
Got it.
我们这就回去
We're on our way.
连接ZPM 我们出发
Hook up the ZPM, we're leaving.
- 等等 我们还不能走
- 你在说什么
- Wait a minute. We can't go.
- What are you talking about?
你说你可以让超光速引擎重新工作的
You said you could get
the hyperdrive back online.
我的意思是 我们可以走 但还不是时候
听着 当Elizabeth接入以后
I mean, we can, but not yet. Look,
while Elizabeth's been connected,
我检查了复制体的基础代码
发现了这个
I've been going over the Replicator's
base code, and I found this.
那是什么
What is that?
圣杯
The Holy Grail.
这是他们存在的所有原因
It's their whole reason for being.
这是一条指挥它们攻击Wraith的命令代码
It's a command code
that directs them to attack the Wraith.
但是它们没有攻击Wraith
But they don't attack the Wraith.
他们在这儿已经10,000年了
They've been sitting on their nanite
asses for 10,000 years.
那是因为它被解除激活了
That's because it's been deactivated.
- 为什么会那样呢
- 我也不清楚
- And how did that happen?
- I've no idea.
也许是古人意识到无法控制它们才这么做的
Maybe the Ancients did it when
they realised they'd lost control.
你现在才注意到?
You're just noticing this now, huh?
这只是数百万基础代码命令中的一条
This is just one in millions
of commands in the base code.
听着 我一直有预感可能会有这样的东西在那儿
Look, I always had a hunch that
something like this might be in there,
但是相信我 并不是很容易就能找到的
but believe me, it was not easy to find.
你能够重新激活它吗
Can you reactivate it?
是的 但是有个问题
Yes, but there's a problem.
听着 我可以重新
对你大脑里的纳米元件编程
Look, I can reprogram
the nanites in your brain
然后通过那条连接
来上传改变的代码 但是...
and use that link
to upload the changes, but
我们必须得等到下一次同步
才能同时影响所有的复制体
we'll need to wait for the next merge to
affect all the Replicators at once, and
但我们还不知道
那会是什么时候 不仅如此
we have no idea when that could be.
Not only that, but
这个过程开启的瞬间
它们就会知道你在那儿
the instant it happens,
they'll know you're there.
就会马上来同化你
They'll take immediate
steps to assimilate you.
那我们就不这么做
Then we're not doing it.
John...你知道这意味着什么
John...
You know what this could mean.
如果复制体和Wraith开战的话
If the Replicators go to war
with the Wraith?
忘掉这个想法吧 不会发生的
Forget about it. It's not happening.
- 这不由你说了算
- 见鬼 不是又如何
- That's not your call.
- The hell it isn't!
别吵了 也许有另一个办法
Hang on. There may be another way.
有一个中央数据核心
There's a central data core.
对所有的复制体来说
它就像是个备份用的硬盘
It's kind of like a back-up
hard-drive for all the Replicators.
如果可以把重新激活的攻击命令
直接上传到那里的话
If I can upload the reactivated
attack command directly into that,
那样我们就不需要利用Elizabeth了
当下一次同步来临
we wouldn't need to use Elizabeth.
We could be half way back to Atlantis
攻击命令生效的时候
我们可能已经在回Atlantis的路上了
when the attack command
takes effect at the next merge.
听上去我更喜欢这个主意
That sounds a little more like it.
是的 还有一个小问题
There's one small problem,
实际上这并不是一个小问题
which is not actually a small problem.
核心在城市的中心 很多层下面
The core is at the center of the city,
several levels down.
想不被发觉到达那里是不可能的
It would be impossible
to get there undetected.
好极了
Great.
等我们把ZPM带回Atlantis 把城市降落后
We're gonna have to come back
after we take the ZPM back to Atlantis
我们再回来
and after we land the City.
我认为我们不会再有第二次机会了
I don't think we'll have another chance.
他说的对
He's right.
一旦他们发现ZPM不见了
Once they notice the ZPM is missing,
他们就能追踪到渗透的源头
they'll be able to trace
the source of the infiltration.
我就再也无法进行这种不被发现的访问
I will never get this kind
of undetected access again.
如果我们要干的话
就不能错过现在的机会
If we're gonna do this,
it's now or never.
你要把隐身场改成反复制体场?
You're gonna turn the cloak
in an anti-Replicator field?
是的 将A.R.G.的控制水晶
Yes, by interfacing
the A.R.G's control crystal
与Jumper的隐身场发生器桥接
with the Jumper's cloaking generator.
唯一的问题是场域能展开到多大
The only question is how far
I can widen the field.
听着 起飞 尽可能到靠近城市中心的地方
Look, go ahead and fly us as close
to the center of the city as possible.
那儿
There.
- 但是我们这样不就会被发现吗
- 是的 我们会被发现
- But won't we be visible?
- Yes, we will.
反复制体场会保护我们
The anti-Replicator field
will protect us.
假设我可以把场域展开足够大
That is, assuming that I can
extend the field wide enough
不仅仅围绕Jumper 还包括核心室
to encompass not only the Jumper,
but also the core room, and
同时还假设 我们能够
足够快到达那里 输入命令
also assuming we can run fast enough
to get there, input the command, and
然后能够赶回来
在复制体想出如何克服它之前 还有...
get back before the Replicators figure
out how to override the field, and...
你知道 屠杀我们之前
You know, slaughter us.
别担心 你不和我们一起去
Don't worry about it.
You're not coming with us.
- Elizabeth也留下
- 抱歉 你说什么
- Neither is Elizabeth.
- I'm sorry, what?
你们通过无线电指引我们 就像上次一样
You guys can guide us through
by radio like you did last time.
等等 如果我不在那里
要如何输入命令
Wait a minute. If I'm not there, how are
we supposed to input the command?
你把它写在平板电脑里
我把它插到核心上 然后上传
Put it on a tablet. I'll plug it
into the core and upload it myself.
插上然后按播放键 是么
什么 你觉得会那么简单吗
Oh, plug and play, huh?
What, you think it's that simple?
会的 因为你会想办法把它变得那么简单
Well, it will be, because
you're gonna make it that simple.
- 是的...
- 我要你
- Yeah...
- I need you
留在这里 Rodney
to stay here, Rodney.
- 为什么
- Rodney
- Why?
- Rodney!
为了盯着我
To keep an eye on me.
你可能需要激活纳米元件的终止程序
You may need to activate
the kill switch on the nanites.
如果我们都留在Jumper里的话
你就能够紧紧盯住我
You'll be able to keep a closer eye on
me if we both stay here in the Jumper.
好吧
Alright.
嘿 别碰那东西
Get out of that.
- 核心就在那个平台下面
- 下面多远
- The core is beneath that platform.
- How far beneath?
9层
Nine levels.
小菜一碟
Piece of cake.
- 有什么发现吗
- 没有
- Anything?
- No.
11次跳跃了
Eleven jumps.
抱歉 即使扫描器的探测距离
得到了显著的提升
I'm sorry. Even with the scanners' range
significantly increased,
目前为止 我们也只完成了很小的区域
we've only covered a small area so far.
在到达起始的Lantian行星之前
我们还要再做39次跳跃
We still have 39 more jumps before
we reach the original Lantian planet.
39?
Thirty nine?
宇宙非常非常大
Space is quite vast.
不用你说
You don't say.
启动超空间引擎
Engage hyperdrive.
第12次跳跃
Stop number twelve.
- 我们现在能被看到
- 反复制体场现在启动
- We're visible.
- Engaging anti-Replicator field now.
起作用了
It's working.
好的 让我们把它扩大
看看能穿透多深
OK, let's jack it up,
see how far we can penetrate.
穿透?
Penetrate?
怎么
What?
好了 现在开始
Alright, here we go.
- 起作用了
- 说得对 起作用了
- It's working.
- Damn right, it's working.
已经包围了核心室 你们可以出发了
It's encompassed the core room.
You're good to go.
怎么 你不相信我 却相信她?
What, you don't believe me,
but you believe her?
我可没恶意
No offense.
但我感觉到了
Offense taken.
一直向下 走9层
Straight down, nine levels.
然后小跑一段走廊就到中心控制室了
Then a short run down a corridor
to the core room.
好了 我编写了一个简单的模块储存传输协议
OK, I've written a basic
block-storage transport protocol
用以将攻击指令从这个平板电脑
直接上载到核心
to upload the attack command
directly from this tablet into the core.
你要做的就是把这个插到主回路中
All you need to do is plug
this cable into the main circuit,
然后它会自动设置并上载指令
it'll automatically configure
and upload the command.
插上插头
Plug it in.
- 你想简单点的
- 我喜欢简单
- You wanted simple.
- I like simple.
我们发明了这种适配器用以
Well, we created that adapter
to interface with Ancient tech,
和复制体喜欢模仿的古人科技进行交互
因此你们不会遇到什么问题
which the Replicators love to imitate,
so you shouldn't have a problem there.
现在 你们动作一定要快
因为一旦他们发现了我们要做的事情
Now, you need to move fast,
because as soon as they find out
就会想出解决的办法
what we're up to, they're going
to figure out a way around it.
像上次那样做就可以了
Just do what you did last time.
我们会很快回来的
We'll be back before you know it.
我们走
Let's go.
怎么了
What is it?
在通讯塔的第2象限
发现反常的能量读数
An anomalous energy reading in the 2nd
quadrant of the communications tower.
- 来源呢
- 还没能确定
- Source?
- Undetermined as of yet.
它在顶层建立了一个向下的分裂力场
It's creating a disruptive field,
emanating downwards from the top level,
一直延伸到正下方的第9层
encompassing nine levels
directly below it.
核心
The core.
好了 我们到了 往左还是往右?
OK, we're here. Left or right?
往左
Left.
那个力场起作用了 Rodney
Shield's working, Rodney.
- 好极了 记住要待在力场里面
- 谢谢提醒
- Good, make sure to stay behind it.
- Thanks for the tip.
现在往右走
Now turn right.
好的 我们到了
Alright, we're here.
我估计那个大大的发光的东西就是核心
I'm assuming the big
glowy thing is the core.
是的 就是那个 好了在控制台上
Indeed, it is. OK,
there should be an open slot
应该有一个可以让你插电缆的接口
in the control panel
that you can plug the cable into.
好的
Alright.
开始
Here goes.
插进去了
It's plugged in.
是吗
It is?
我怎么什么都没看到
你确定你插进了正确的接口吗
Why am I not reading anything? Are you
sure you plugged it into the right slot?
这里只有一个接口 Rodney
There's only one slot, Rodney.
快点 John 他们来了 有几百个
Hurry, John, they're coming,
and there's hundreds of them.
- 力场不是会保护我们的吗
- 只要你动作够快
- Won't the field protect us?
- As long as you hurry.
好的 听着 试试拔出来再重新插一次
OK, look, try plugging it in again.
好了 重新插进去了
Alright, it's plugged in again.
还是没反应 你做了什么
Still nothing. What did you do?
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything.
他们在不断攻击力场
They keep attacking the field.
他们故意牺牲自己
They're deliberately
sacrificing themselves.
他们为什么要那么做
Why would they do that?
他们攻击力场的次数越多
The more they attack the field,
就能越快找出穿过力场的方法
the quicker they can figure out
how to override it.
那我们得赶快离开这儿了
Then we need to get the hell ot of here.
Rodney 为什么会不起作用
Rodney, why is this not working?
不起作用是因为核心
无法识别平板电脑
It's not working because
the core is not recognizing the tablet.
好的 为什么不行
Why not?
听着 我不知道
I don't know!
- 我们几乎就要穿越力场了
- 好的
- We're almost through the field.
- Good.
我去了
I'm on my way.
好吧 你需要将对话协议进行调整
You need to implement
adjustments in the negotiation protocol
使装置交互能够并行
to exploit parallelism
at the device interface.
- 什么
- 只管照我说的做
- What?
- Just do what I say.
先拔出插头 现在进入平板电脑的根目录
Start by unplugging the cable.
Access the tablet's root directory.
这可不简单了
This is not simple.
- 你得马上让他们出来
- 我们还没完成
- You have to get them out of there.
- We're not done...
已经没有时间了
复制体已经突破力场了
There's no more time!
The Replicators have breached the field!
你说他们突破立场了是什么意思
What do you mean
they breached the field?
他们找到了穿越它的方法
听着 我们的动作还要再快些
They figured how to override it.
Look, we need to move much faster.
你得做些改动使对话协议
You need to make changes
to the negotiation protocol
允许直接的数据安置
to allow for direct data placement.
我们需要考虑到数据流中数据包边界
We need to allow for resynchronization
of the packet boundaries
的重新同步
within the data stream.
Oberoth往核心室去了
Oberoth is heading to the core room.
- 他知道是我们
- 有多远
- He knows it's us.
- How far is he?
- 他们能逃掉吗
- 不行
- Can they make a run for it?
- No.
复制体正从四面八方围上来
他们被困住了
Replicators are apoaching
from every direction. They're trapped.
也就是说他们等于是挂了
Which means they're as good as dead.
要知道我们能听到你说话
We can hear you, you know.
什么 噢 不
What? No.
我说等于是挂了
其实意思更倾向于...
When I say, "as good as dead,"
I mean it as more of a...
- Elizabeth 你要干嘛
- 呆在这儿
- Elizabeth, what are you doing?
- Stay here!
Elizabeth 你不能出去
Elizabeth, you can't go out there!
- Elizabeth
- 发生什么事了 Rodney
- Elizabeth!
- What's going on?
- Elizabeth刚刚离开了Jumper
- 为什么
- Elizabeth just left the jumper.
- Why?
我不知道 她就这么跑出去了
I don't know. She just ran out.
Elizabeth 我是Sheppard
你能听到吗
Elizabeth, this is Sheppard,
do you copy?
请回答
Respond.
- 如果他们抓到她
- 我知道 我知道
- If they capture her...
- I know, I know.
那么 我们现在怎么办
So, what do we do now?
她说过如果她有可疑的举动
就打开纳米元件的终止开关
She said to hit the kill switch on the
nanites if she did anything suspicious.
我知道 但是...
I know, but...
Sheppard...
Sheppard.
下命令吧
Make the call.
动手吧
Do it.
- 它不起作用了
- 什么
- It's not working.
- What?
- 为什么不起作用
- 给我点儿时间
- Why not?
- Just... give me a second.
我没得到信息确认 还有 别再问为什么
因为我不知道 好么
I'm not getting confirmation, and don't
ask why, because I don't know, OK?
我的意思是 上一次
她体内有活跃纳米元件时
The last time she had
active nanites inside her,
她能够施加一定程度的控制
也许 也许她现在正在那么做
she was able to exert a certain control.
Maybe she's doing it here now, or...
又或者有干扰影响了频率
maybe there's interference
that's affecting the frequency.
我不知道 我得运行诊断程序
I don't know.
I need to run a diagnostic.
你为什么不想个方法
把我们弄出去呢
Better yet, why don't you figure out
a way how to get us out here?
即使我们完了 也要把任务完成了
If we're screwed, we might
as well complete the mission.
Weir博士?
Dr. Weir?
你好 Oberoth
Hello, Oberoth.
你很吃惊
You're surprised.
是的 我是很惊讶
Indeed, I am.
Niam用纳米元件感染了我
Niam infected me with nanites.
是的 我发觉了
Yes, I can detect them now.
我们把它们中和了
We were able to neutralize them,
并重行编程
and then reprogram
为我们所用
and manipulate them to suit our needs.
你们真勤奋
Industrious of you.
这也就是为什么我能通过你
建立一个物理链接
Which is why, now that I've been able to
establish a physical link through you,
我直接进入了全部复制体
I have direct access
to the Replicator collective.
现在全由我掌控了
I'm in control now.
好了 我插进去了 怎么样
OK, I'm plugged in. Anything?
好了 好了 起作用了
Yes! Yes, it's working!
发生了什么事
What the hell just happened?
复制体都不动了
The Replicators have all frozen.
是的 我看得见 但是谁做的呢
Well, I can see that, but who did it?
不是我
It wasn't me.
应该是Elizabeth
It might have been Elizabeth.
- 她能做到吗
- 我不知道 我是说
- Can she do that?
- I don't know. I mean,
她必须与全部复制体进行直接链接
也就是说
she'd have to link directly
with the collective, which means the
他们控制她的纳米元件的可能性
成几何级数地增长
chances they'll be able to take over her
nanites have increased exponentially.
他们活过来要多少时间
How long before they come back to life?
我也想问这个问题 但我更愿意相信
Your guess is as good as mine,
but I would err on the side of less time
- 时间不多了
- 我们能走了吗
- rather than more.
- So we go?
是的 先把重要的事做了 上载如何了
Yeah, first things first. How are we
doing with the upload?
就要好了 还要几秒钟
Almost there. Just a few more seconds.
- 多少秒
- 别再这么问我了
- How many seconds?
Don't start with that again!
你的力量让我印象深刻
I'm impressed with your strength,
Weir博士 但我必须提醒你
我进行必要的修整
Dr. Weir, but I must remind you,
that it's only a matter of time
并摆脱你的控制
before I make the necessary corrections
只是个时间问题
to overcome the hold you have on me.
我做好了一直斗下去的准备
I am prepared to fight
for as long as I need.
很伟大
Good for you.
你保护自己人的愿望值得赞赏
Your desire to protect
your people is admirable,
但最终 你会
but you will, ultimately,
失败的
fail.
继续那么想吧
Keep thinking that.
继续让你的高傲埋葬自己吧
Keep allowing your arrogance
to undermine you.
你知道这是事实 Weir博士
You know it's true, Dr. Weir.
我能感受到你已经开始变弱了
I can feel you weakening already.
即便有斗争的欲望
Despite your desire
但这对你来说...
this is a fight for which you are...
很明显是一场
clearly
缺乏准备的战斗
ill-equipped.
好了 完成了 拔下插头快走
That's it, you're done! Unplug and go!
再说一遍
Once again,
你低估了我
you have underestimated me.
他们又开始动了
They're moving again!
是的 我知道
Yeah. I know.
好吧
Well,
这真是熟悉的场景
this is familiar.
我正在想你们的这次入侵
I'm trying to decide
if this incursion of yours
表现了你们出奇的勇敢 还是...
reflects considerable bravery or
- 愚蠢
- Weir博士在哪儿
- stupidity.
- Where's Dr. Weir?
想要对我们全体进行控制的尝试
Her attempts to seize
control of the collective
使她不堪重负
proved too taxing for her,
她的生理与心理均陷于濒死的境地
rendering her mind and body
virtually moribund.
她已经被带去...
She has been taken to be...
修理了
repaired.
- 你们想要控制她
- 我们已经做到了
- You're gonna take control of her.
- That has already occurred.
不幸的是 我没法
Unfortunately, I was not able to
从她那里收集我想要的所有信息
glean all the information
I need from her,
所以我不得不从你们身上拿
so I will have to extract it from you.
信息?
Information?
有关Atlantis的精确位置
About the precise location of Atlantis.
在我们摧毁它之前
你们逃离了那个星球
You left your planet before
we were able to destroy it.
对毁了你们的计划深表遗憾
Sorry to spoil your plans.
没什么被毁
Nothing is spoiled,
只是被延长了
merely prolonged,
而现在 由于你们的帮助
and now, with your help,
我们将完成对它的毁灭
we will complete the destruction.
你看 我们当中没人会主动告诉你信息...
Seeing how none of us
will volunteer the information...
你清楚地知道
You know quite well
我们有一个简单的方法
来获取我们需要的信息
that we have a simple method
for extracting what we need.
有问题吗
Problems?
什么
What?
我知道 你会摆弄我们的思想
I figured, you'd messed with our minds,
所以我扰乱了你的思想
so I'd mess with yours.
你并不比我强大 Oberoth
You didn't overpower me, Oberoth.
复制体守卫并没有抓住我的小队
The Replicator guards
didn't capture my team.
那些只是在你脑中虚构的场景
It was all a fictional scenario
played out in your mind.
现实中 你的守卫还被冻结着
In reality,
your guards are still frozen,
而我的小队在我们说话的当口逃跑了
and my team is escaping as we speak.
你错了 Oberoth
You were wrong, Oberoth.
我从来都没有低估你
I have never underestimated you,
但你明显低估了我
but you have clearly underestimated me.
你不会活着离开这座城市的
You will not leave this city alive!
也许不会
Maybe not,
但我的队伍会
but my team will.
- 还是没有Elizabeth的消息么
- 没有
- Still nothing from Elizabeth?
- No.
我联系不到她 追踪不到她
好像她就...就这么消失了
Can't communicate with her or track her.
It's like she just... disappeared.
如果是她让复制体无法活动的
If she's the one
who froze the Replicators,
那就是说 她很可能还活着
that means she's probably still alive.
目前来看 是有可能
For the moment, maybe.
- 她离这儿不会太远的
- 我们会找到她的
- She can't be that far.
- We'll find her.
好吧 你们最好快点
那些复制体随时都有可能解冻
You better make it fast. The Replicators
could unfreeze at any moment.
谢谢 Rodney
Thanks, Rodney!
我很欣赏你的坚韧
I admire your tenacity,
但我不会被愚弄第二次
but I won't be fooled again.
你在挣扎 Weir博士
You're struggling, Dr. Weir.
快去Jumper
Get to the jumper!
你得和我们一起走
You're coming with us.
我没法再让他们冰冻下去了
I can't keep them frozen much longer!
我们不会抛下你的
We're not leaving you behind!
如果你们现在不走
If you don't leave right now,
那我们就没人能逃出去了 所以快走
none of us will get out of here, so go!
这是命令
That's an order!
- 走吧
- Elizabeth
Come on!
快走
Go!
哦 谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
我们能隐身么
Can we cloak?
Rodney 我们能隐身么
Rodney, can we cloak?
不 还不行
No, Not yet.
不行 把隐身转换为AR场耗费了太多的能量
We drained too much power trying
to convert the cloak into an AR field.
听着 我正尝试接驳ZPM 但需要些时间
I'll try to interface the ZPM,
but we're going to need some time.
好吧 我们尽量争取时间
Alright, we'll just have
to make a run for it then.
超空间引擎怎么样
How's hyperspace looking?
不怎么样 要知道
从ZPM中汲取能量很需要技巧
Not good. Harnessing power
from the ZPM is tricky.
如果我错了哪怕一丁点儿数量 那么
If I'm off even
a slightest amount, then
- 我们都会...
- 有两艘飞船正往这来
- we could all...
- Two ships heading our way.
- Rodney
- 我需要再多一点时间
- Rodney!
- I need more time!
我们刚刚失去了武器系统
We just lost weapons!
- 可恶
- 快点 Mckay
- Dammit!
- Come on, McKay!
这可不简单 你知道吗
This is not simple, you know?
如果我不正确校准能量输出 那我们可能
If I don't properly calibrate the power
output, we could incinerate the moment
在超空间窗口打开的那一刹那就烧成灰烬
the hyperspace window opens!
我们正前方有什么东西
I'm picking something up dead ahead.
噢 该死
Oh, crap.
他们在给武器补充能量
They're powering up weapons!
那是什么
What the hell was that?
Sheppard中校 这里是Apollo号
你听到了吗
Colonel Sheppard, this is the Apollo,
do you read?
Ellis上校 是你吗
Colonel Ellis, is that you?
是的 302号堤岸已经开启
Affirmative. The 302 bay is open,
你们可以登陆 我建议你们尽快
and you have permission to come aboard.
I suggest you hurry.
收到 Apollo号 我们这就去
Copy that, Apollo. We're on our way.
我能不能补充一句
你们这时间算的真他妈完美
Can I just add that your timing
is pretty damn perfect?
我们原本能早些到这儿的
但我们寻找Atlantis时出了点小麻烦
We would've got here earlier, but we had
a little trouble finding Atlantis.
Sam? 等等 是你吗
Wait, is that you?
是我 Rodney
你上船后我会向你解释
It's me, Rodney.
I'll explain when you get onboard.
上校...
Colonel...
Weir博士被困在复制体星球上 你们能...
We lost Dr. Weir
on the Replicator planet. Can you...
锁定她的定位器信标把她光传上来吗
lock on her locator beacon
and beam her up?
我没获得任何信号
I'm not picking up any signal.
收到
Copy that.
这里有个不错的 M35-117
Here's a good one, M35-117.
- Weir博士知道吗
- 不 这不在我们的首选和后备列表上
- Does Dr. Weir know about it?
- Not on our primary or back-up list.
我着意地选择了一个
我们以前没考虑过的星球
I purposefully searched for a planet
we'd never considered before.
复制体可以在她的脑中
探测想要的信息 但不会发现这个
The Replicators can probe her mind
all they want, they won't find it.
很好...
Good...
- 对我们而言
- 好了 听着 那里...
- For us.
- Well, look, it's a...
有稳定的大气 一片巨大的海洋
stable atmosphere, a big ocean.
有些不仅很大 而且
Besides the large, particularly
很像毒蛇的生物在大陆栖息
venomous snake-like creature
that inhabits the main land,
看来是个很好客的环境
it looks to be a welcoming environment.
好的 Radek 进度怎么样
Alright. Radek, how we doing?
全设定好了 ZPM已经接入系统
All set here. The ZPM is online.
好了
OK,
我们开始吧
here we go.
我们做到了
We did it.
好了 让这个城市降落还有些小问题
Well, there's still the small matter
of landing this thing.
我会跳上控制椅 慢慢地把我们降下去
I'll just jump in the chair,
ease us down.
好吧 那可是很有技术性的
Well, that could be tricky.
我们光到这儿就消耗了ZPM很多能量
We drained a lot of power
from the ZPM just getting here.
我们有足够的能量确保
护盾能够支持我们再入
We got enough energy to keep
the shield up for re-entry.
最好是那样 一个如此大的城市
会产生可观的摩擦热量
There better be. A City this size
will create considerable friction.
如果我们进入得太快
角度太倾斜 护盾就会...
We come in too fast
or too steep, and the shield
在压力作用下减弱
那么整个城市就会分崩离析
could attenuate under the stress,
the whole place will be torn to shreds
或被烧毁 也可能两者都有
or burn up, or both...
要知道 你总是不知道停下
It never ends with you, you know?
什么
What?
让所有人都系上安全带 我们要着陆了
Tell everyone to buckle up.
We're going in.
护盾维持中 目前为止很好
Shield's holding. So far so good.
- 出什么问题了
- 倾角太大了
- What's wrong?
- Angle's too steep.
如果继续这样 会造成护盾太多的拉伸应变
Like this, we're gonna put
too much strain on the shield,
也就是说要从ZPM汲取更多的能量
which means more power draining
from the ZPM.
Sheppard 倾角太大了
Sheppard, we're coming in too steep.
我们要减小再入的角度
We need to ease up
on the angle of re-entry.
事实上 应该是进入
你看 我们从来没有离开过这里...
In fact, you mean entry.
You see, we never actually left this...
噢 好的 好的
Right, right.
减小角度
Ease up on the angle!
你第一次说的时候我就听到了 Rodney
I heard you the first time, Rodney.
但我们的角度还是太大了
And yet we're still coming in too steep!
抓紧
Hang on!
我们要到达海洋了
We're over the ocean!
Sheppard 你得把速度慢下来
我们要进入水中了
Sheppard you need to slow us down.
We're coming in over the water.
收到
Copy that.
还是太快 减速
Still too fast! Slow down!
我们要缓缓降落
We want to touch down gently, like
就像叶子轻触池塘的水面
like a leaf kissing
the surface of a pond.
不错的轻触
Nice kissing.
情况怎么样
How we doing?
系统看起来不错...
Systems are looking good...
到目前为止
So far,
ZPM也有充足的能量
and plenty of power in the ZPM.
解除护盾
Drop the shield.
Sheppard中校 我们成功了
Colonel Sheppard, we made it.
城市安全地漂浮在海面上
The City's floating safely on the ocean.
出色的降落
Excellent landing.
谢谢
Thank you.
你觉得谁会来代替她
Who d'you think's gonna replace her?
我不知道
I don't know.
无论是谁...
Whoever it is...
这都是个苦差事
That's tough shoes to fill.
是的
Yes.
- 好了 让我们试试看
- 好的
- OK, let's give it a go.
- Right.
这里是Atlantis 呼叫星门指挥部
This is Atlantis,
calling Stargate Command.
听得到么
Do you read?
听到了 Atlantis 很高兴听到你们的声音
We read you, Atlantis.
Good to hear from you.
我们也是
Great to be heard.
告诉Landry将军 我们返回到了节点内
Tell General Landry
we're back on the grid.
Rodney...
什么
What?
远程扫描仪探测到
Long-range scanners detect a massive
有一只巨大的舰队从复制体行星启程了
fleet of ships being launched
from the Replicator planet,
但他们不是往这里来的
but they're not heading for us.
那是个Wraith的行星
That's a Wraith planet.
攻击指令一定是被激活了
The attack command
must have been activated.
你们明白么 它起作用了
What do you know? It worked!
你在这儿
There you are.
2个月亮
Two moons.
事实上 有5个
Actually, there are five.
只是肉眼仅能看到2个
It's just these these are only two
visible to the naked eye.
-真的么
-是的
- Really?
- Yeah.
听说你和Rodney重新帮我们
连上了星系间桥接
Heard you and Rodney got us reconnected
to the intergalactic bridge.
是的
Yeah.
Landry将军听到消息后松了一口气
General Landry was understandably
relieved to hear from us.
要知道 经历了那么多
我都没什么机会祝贺你
You know, in all the excitement I never
got a chance to congratulate you.
你晋升了 是个戴鹰上校了
(空军校官中的最高军衔)
Your promotion.
You're a full bird Colonel now.
噢 谢谢
Thank you.
- 那么 你会呆在这儿?
- 不
- So you sticking around?
- No.
Landry将军希望Lee博士和我从星门回去
General Landry wants
Dr. Lee and I to gate back,
把这里情况向他做一份详细简报
give him a full briefing
on the situation here.
眼下 Apollo号还会留在轨道上
The Apollo's gonna remain
in orbit for a while
以防你们需要什么帮助
in case you need any assistance.
谢谢你从坏人手上救了我们
Thanks for saving our asses
back there from the bad guys.
那真是兵行险招
That was a risky move.
和你与你的小队经历的危险相比
那些根本不算什么
It was nothing compared to the risk
that you and your team took.
坦白地说 你能做到这些
让我感到非常吃惊
Frankly, I'm amazed that
you were able to pull it off.
我得到了很多帮助
We had a lot of help.
是的
Yeah.
Landry将军表示哀悼
General Landry sends his condolences.
他在听到Weir博士的事后 感到非常悲恸
He was deeply saddened
to hear about Dr. Weir.
我们都是
We all were.
我还没有放弃希望
I haven't given up hope.
只要有一线她还活着的机会
If there's a chance she's still alive,
我就会找到她
I'll find her.
我知道
I know.